RAJAT SRIVASTAVA

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

🔾 rajat19.github.io 📞 9910364830 **♀** Delhi in rajatsriv19 O rajat19

EDUCATION

Ajay Kumar Garg Engineering College, Ghaziabad

BTech Computer Science 2017 Graduated with 80.68% Member of Open Source R&D Team Organized Tech Events in College

AWARDS

Sept. 2020 Paytm · ROCKSTAR

Oct. 2019 Paytm · ROCKSTAR

SUMMARY

Highly effective software developer offering a wealth of around 5 years of relevant expertise. A valuable team player who also is personable and dedicated. Seeking the chance to bring further success to an established organisation through development, testing, and software debugging.

SKILLS

BACKEND DEVELOPMENT: Java, Node js, Python, Javascript, SpringBoot

DATA STORES: Mysql, Mongo DB, Cassandra, Redis, Aerospike

OTHER TECHNOLOGIES: Git, Jenkins, Apache Storm, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Docker,

GraphQL, Debezium, Apache Spark

EMPLOYMENT

INDEED.COM

Senior Software Engineer

Hyderabad, India May 2022 to Current, May 2022 to Current

- Working on Discovery and Indeed Apply chat bot system using Java and React

MYNTRA DESIGNS

Bangalore Aug. 2021 to Apr. 2022 Senior Software Engineer

- Designed and Developed Near Realtime System with Java to update Myntra Inventory on Facebook/Google Ads
- Worked on improving monitoring of systems through use of prometheus
- Working on improvement of Myntra's Gateway platform which is the single point for receiving all of the traffic
- Worked on design and implementation of multiple datacenter support for dynamic configuration system Switch

PAYTM Noida Sept. 2018 to July 2021 Senior Software Engineer

- Worked on realtime streaming data for processing and analytics purposes
- Worked on distributed computation system like Apache Storm and Spark Streaming
- Worked on Multi-tiered Aggregation System for fraud detection using Apache Spark
- Worked with distributed messaging system for asynchronous processing of rewards for user
- Worked on Integration of ScratchCard Service with Paytm's chat system using Kafka and Storm
- Worked on Core features for Paytm Cricket League and Diwali Tambola Game
- Developed Paytm's Scratch Card System using Java and Mysql
- Developed Paytm's lucky draw feature using Node.js
- Worked on integration of Payment Bank's pipeline with Paytm reward system
- Developed realtime gratification and multiple gratification for Paytm's reward system using Java

SMARTPRIX WEB Noida Software Developer June 2017 to Aug. 2018

- Designed Node JS and Vue JS based admin web applications.
- Developed Smartprix new website using Node JS and Marko JS
- Developed Smartrank, an online IDE for test purposes
- Worked on Smartprix Crawler to extract data from appropriate websites

SYSBIOME TECHNOLOGIES

Intern

Noida June 2016 to July 2016

- Developed Samarpan project for recruitment purpose using Laravel
- Wrote all technical documentation for new software
- Developed native Android mobile applications for Samarpan.

JUSTWRAVEL Noida Sept. 2015 to Nov. 2015

- Worked on JustWravel.com using Codelgniter framework
- Provided continued maintenance and development of bug fixes and patch sets for existing web applications

PERSONAL PROJECTS

ISNIPER

Node cli based project that creates new projects based on already provided templates. Hosted on npm and github packages

KEEP IN TOUCH

Application that reminds its customers to keep in touch with their dear ones. Reminders can be scheduled as per convenience. Build using node is

TORRENT CRAWLER

Python based command line interface to fetch torrents and subtitles for a movie. Hosted on pypi

HACKERRANK CRAWLER

Crawl Hackerrank Solutions using command line using python. Hosted on pypi